Guide to the George A. Lindbeck Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Writings, 1941-2006, n.d.; Series II
  - Addendum
    - Edited works
      - Background correspondence related to Robert Calhoun Lectures Project and samples of editing of chapters., 1980s (Box 92, Folder 17-18)
    - Reviews
      - Reviews of: Biblical Hermeneutics in Historical Perspective (Mark Burrows and Paul Rorem, eds.), Canon and Criterion in Christian Theology (William Abraham), The Uncommitted (K. Keniston), By the Renewing of Your Minds (Ellen Charry), and Die Rechtfertigung des Suenders--Rettungshandeln Gottes oder historisches Interpretament? (Gottfried Martens), 1992-2000 (Box 72, Folder 157)
      - Reviews of: The Church in a Postliberal Age, 2003 (Box 89, Folder 26)
      - Review of Holy Scripture: Revelation, Inspiration & Interpretation (Donald G. Bloesch), 1994 (Box 89, Folder 15)
      - "Theological Method and Philosophy of Science" - review of books by Frei, Kelsey, Peukert, Koloman, Pannenberg, Tracy (Box 90, Folder 13)
      - Review of three books re. Bonhoeffer, n.d. (Box 90, Folder 14)
- Regarding The Nature of Doctrine, 1976-1988, n.d.; Series III
  - Book Reviews by Others (incl. M. E. Marty, J.C. Shelley, M. Van Hamersveld), nd (Box 15, Folder 301)
  - Articles by Others (esp. T. Sherry, The Nature of Doctrine and the Language of Faith, and A. Dulles, Observations on George A. Lindbeck, "The Nature of Doctrine" ) (Box 15, Folder 302)
  - Articles by Others (incl. W. Meeks, Interpreting the New Testament in a Post-Lindbeck Age, and B. Childs, Childs on Lindbeck: A Response ) (Box 15, Folder 303)
  - Articles by Others (incl. D. Tracy, Lindbeck's New Program for Theology, and M.F. Wiles, Comments on George Lindbeck's "Theories of Religion and 'Method in Theology'" ) (Box 15, Folder 304)
  - Articles by Others (incl. J. E. Thiel, Theological Authorship: Postmodern Alternatives?, and M. Root, Truth, Relativism, and Postliberal Theology ) (Box 15, Folder 305)
  - Re. dissertation by Hans-Joachim Tambour, "Theologischer Pragmatismus. Uberlegungen zum kulturell-sprachlichen Ansatz von Geore A. Lindbeck", 2002 (Box 92, Folder 5)
  - Articles: Responses by Lindbeck (Box 15, Folder 306)
  - Background Materials (incl. P. Winch, Language, Belief and Relativism, and P. Chirico, Religious Experience and Development of Dogma ) (Box 15, Folder 307)
- Notes / Research Materials, 1965-1999, n.d.; Series IV
  - Original files
    - Creeds and Confessions (Box 16, Folder 308)
    - Ecumenism, nd (Box 16, Folder 309)
    - Seven Schools Conference, nd (Box 16, Folder 310)
    - Student Writings, nd (Box 16, Folder 311)
    - Theological Education, nd (Box 16, Folder 312-313)
    - Miscellaneous, nd (Box 16, Folder 314-316)
    - Miscellaneous, 1965-1988, nd (Box 56, Folder 1313)
    - Reading Notes, nd (Box 16, Folder 317-319)
    - Journals, nd (Box 17, Folder 320-324)
  - Addendum
    - Asian Christianity, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 33-36)
    - Biblical interpretation, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 37)
    - Biblical interpretation, n.d. (Box 61, Folder 38-45)
    - Culture and religion (Box 62, Folder 46)
    - Ecclesiology, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 47-48)
    - Ecumenism, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 49-55)
    - Ecumenism, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 56-63)
    - Ecumenism, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 64-73)
    - Ecumenism, n.d. (Box 90, Folder 15)
    - Ecumenism, n.d. (Box 90, Folder 16)
    - Frei, Hans, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 74-75)
    - Homosexuality, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 76-80)
    - Judaism, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 81)
    - Judaism, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 82-88)
    - Judaism, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 89-93)
    - Justification, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 94-97)
    - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 98-101)
    - Philosophy, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 102-104)
    - Princeton Center of Theological Inquiry (C.T.I.) research, 1999 (Box 68, Folder 105-106)
    - Princeton Center of Theological Inquiry (C.T.I.) research, 1999 (Box 69, Folder 107-114)
    - Sociology of religion, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 115-116)
    - Theology, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 117-122)
    - Theology, n.d. (Box 71, Folder 123-125)
    - Theology, 1985, n.d. (Box 89, Folder 2)
    - Theology, n.d. (Box 90, Folder 17)
    - Theology (Box 92, Folder 15)
- Course Related Materials, nd; Series V
  - Original files
    - Philosophy I: Philosophy of Religion, nd (Box 18, Folder 325)
    - Religion IB: Directed Studies, nd (Box 18, Folder 326)
    - Philosophy 10a: Logic, nd (Box 18, Folder 327)
    - Philosophy 10b: Logic, nd (Box 18, Folder 328)
    - Philosophy 10b: Logic, nd (Box 18, Folder 329)
    - Philosophy 12b:Introduction to Problems of Philosophy, nd (Box 18, Folder 330)
    - Philosophy S12-A, nd (Box 18, Folder 331)
    - Philosophy 14: History of Philosophy, nd (Box 18, Folder 332)
    - Philosophy 23: Social and Political Philosophy (Box 18, Folder 333)
    - Religion 25a: Contemporary Roman Catholicism, nd (Box 18, Folder 334)
    - Religious Studies 25b: Roman Catholicism Since Vatican II, nd (Box 18, Folder 335)
    - Religion 29: History of Christianity (1350 to Present), nd (Box 18, Folder 336)
    - Philosophy 30b: Philosophy of Religion, nd (Box 18, Folder 337)
    - Philosophy 31a: Medieval Philosophy, nd (Box 18, Folder 338)
    - Philosophy 31b: History of Philosophy, nd (Box 18, Folder 339)
    - Philosophy 38a/Philosophy 31a, nd (Box 19, Folder 340)
    - Philosophy 38a: Medieval Philosophy, nd (Box 19, Folder 341)
    - Philosophy 39a, nd (Box 19, Folder 342)
    - Religion 39a: The Reformation and the Age of Reason (Box 19, Folder 343)
    - Philosophy 39b: Medieval Philosophy: The Nature of Man, nd (Box 19, Folder 344)
    - Religion 39b: Reformation and the Age of Reason (Box 19, Folder 345)
    - Religious Studies 44: Senior Seminar, nd (Box 19, Folder 346)
    - Philosophy 50b: Spinoza, nd (Box 19, Folder 347)
    - Religion 72a: Comparative Dogmatics, nd (Box 19, Folder 348)
    - Religion 110b: New Testament Interpretation, nd (Box 19, Folder 349)
    - Philosophy 111/Religion 111: The Idea of God in Western Thought, nd (Box 19, Folder 350)
    - Philosophy 112/Religion 112: Modern Religious Philosophers, nd (Box 19, Folder 351)
    - Religion 123b: Introduction to Protestant Theology, nd (Box 19, Folder 352)
    - Philosophy 125: History of Religion, nd (Box 19, Folder 353)
    - Philosophy 131: Medieval Philosophy, nd (Box 19, Folder 354)
    - Religion 131a: Systematic Theology, nd (Box 19, Folder 355)
    - Religion 143: Studies in the Relations between Religion and Literature (Box 19, Folder 356)
    - Religion 144b: Christianity and Contemporary Culture (Box 19, Folder 357)
    - Religion 146a: History of Philosophy: Thales to Descartes, nd (Box 19, Folder 358)
    - Religion 166f: The Study of Society, nd (Box 19, Folder 359)
    - Religion 200a: History of Christianity, nd (Box 19, Folder 360)
    - Philosophy 213a, nd (Box 19, Folder 361)
    - Religion 213b/Philosophy 213b, nd (Box 19, Folder 362)
    - Religion 214a: Contemporary Roman Catholic Theology, nd (Box 19, Folder 363)
    - Religion 214a: Contemporary Roman Catholic Theology, nd (Box 20, Folder 364)
    - Religion 214b: Church Ecclesiology, nd (Box 20, Folder 365)
    - Religion 214b: Church Ecclesiology, nd (Box 20, Folder 366)
    - Religion 214b: Comparative Dogmatics, nd (Box 20, Folder 367)
    - Religion 218a: Seminar in Contemporary Roman Catholic Theology, nd (Box 20, Folder 368)
    - Religion 224a: Social Setting of Religious Ethics, nd (Box 20, Folder 369)
    - Philosophy 230: Philosophical Theology, nd (Box 20, Folder 370)
    - Religion 231b: Christian Theology from Augustine through the Reformation, nd (Box 20, Folder 371)
    - Religion 236a: Augustine Seminar, nd (Box 20, Folder 372)
    - Religion 240: Systematic Theology, nd (Box 20, Folder 373)
    - Religion 240a: Comparative Dogmatics, nd (Box 20, Folder 374)
    - Religion 240b: Comparative Dogmatics, nd (Box 21, Folder 375)
    - Religion 240b: Comparative Dogmatics, nd (Box 21, Folder 376)
    - Religion 242b: Seminar in Aquinas, nd (Box 21, Folder 377)
    - Religion 252a: Seminar in Medieval and Reformation Thought (Box 21, Folder 378)
    - Religious Studies 256a: Theological Methodology: Tracy and Lonergan (Box 21, Folder 379)
    - Religious Studies 262b: Theological Methodology: Rahner and Lonergan (Box 21, Folder 380)
    - Religion 262b: Issues in Jewish-Christian Dialogue (Box 21, Folder 381)
    - Religion 265a: Seminar in Reformation and Pre-Reformation Thought: Luther and Augustine (Box 21, Folder 382)
    - Religion 266b, nd (Box 21, Folder 383)
    - Religion 304: History of Philosophy, nd (Box 21, Folder 384)
    - Religion 304a: Western Philosophical Thought About God, nd (Box 21, Folder 385)
    - Religion 304b: History of Western Philosophical Thought About God, nd (Box 21, Folder 386)
    - Religion 330b: Theology and Aesthetics (Box 22, Folder 387)
    - Religion 338: Philosophical Theology, nd (Box 22, Folder 388)
    - Religion 340a: The Sociology of Knowledge and Theology (Box 22, Folder 389)
    - Religious Studies 349a/718a: Seminar in Contemporary Roman Catholic Theology: Christology, nd (Box 22, Folder 390)
    - Religion 365a: Medieval Tradition, nd (Box 22, Folder 391)
    - Religion 365b: The Natural Theology of Thomas Aquinas, nd (Box 22, Folder 392)
    - Religious Studies 442c, nd (Box 22, Folder 393)
    - Religion 464a: A Survey of the Christian Movement in Asia in the 20th Century, nd (Box 22, Folder 394)
    - Religion 700a: History of Christianity: The Church in Ancient and Medieval Times (Box 22, Folder 395)
    - Religion 700b: History of Christianity II, nd (Box 22, Folder 396)
    - Religion 705b: History of Christian Thought in the West (450-1650), nd (Box 22, Folder 397)
    - Religion 711b: Confessional Theology of the Reformation Period, nd (Box 22, Folder 398)
    - Relgion 717a: Comparative Doctrine, nd (Box 22, Folder 399)
    - Religion 718a: Seminar in Contemporary Roman Catholic Theology: Christology, nd (Box 22, Folder 400)
    - Religion 721b: History of Christian Thought in the West (405-1650), nd (Box 22, Folder 401)
    - Religion 724b: Confessional Theology of the Reformation Period, nd (Box 22, Folder 402)
    - Religion 710b, nd (Box 22, Folder 403)
    - Religion 711a: Aquinas and Some Interpreters (Box 22, Folder 404)
    - Religion 728a: Nature and Order of the Church (Box 22, Folder 405)
    - Religion 728a: Comparative Doctrine, nd (Box 22, Folder 406)
    - Religion 728a: Comparative Doctrine, nd (Box 22, Folder 407)
    - Religion 732b: Reformation Confessions, nd (Box 22, Folder 408)
    - Religion 732b: Reformation Confessions, nd (Box 22, Folder 409)
    - Religion 732b: Reformation Confessions, nd (Box 22, Folder 410)
    - Religion 732b: Reformation Confessions, nd (Box 23, Folder 411)
    - Religion 744a/745a: Comparative Doctrine, nd (Box 23, Folder 412)
    - Religion 749b: Seminar in Contemporary Roman Catholic Theology: Hans Urs von Balthasar's View and Use of Scripture (Box 23, Folder 413)
    - Religious Studies 857a: Karl Rahner, nd (Box 23, Folder 414)
    - Christian Ethics, nd (Box 23, Folder 415)
    - Christology Seminar, nd (Box 23, Folder 416)
    - Christology in the Fathers, nd (Box 23, Folder 417)
    - Comparative Doctrine, nd (Box 23, Folder 418)
    - Comparative Dogmatics, nd (Box 23, Folder 419-422)
    - Contemporary Roman Catholic Theology: Rahner, von Balthasar, Tracy, nd (Box 24, Folder 423)
    - Contemporary Theology, nd (Box 24, Folder 424)
    - Devotional Reading, nd (Box 24, Folder 425)
    - European Church History, nd (Box 24, Folder 426)
    - Geology, nd (Box 24, Folder 427)
    - History of Doctrine, nd (Box 24, Folder 428)
    - The History of the Expansion of Christianity, nd (Box 25, Folder 429)
    - History of Philosophy, nd (Box 25, Folder 430-431)
    - Homiletics, nd (Box 25, Folder 432)
    - Hooker and Luther (Box 25, Folder 433)
    - Luther, nd (Box 25, Folder 434)
    - Lutheran Identity, nd (Box 25, Folder 435)
    - Medieval Philosophy, nd (Box 25, Folder 436)
    - Medieval Scholasticism, nd (Box 25, Folder 437)
    - Metaphysics of Aquinas, nd (Box 25, Folder 438)
    - Metaphysics, nd (Box 25, Folder 439)
    - Modern Theology, nd (Box 25, Folder 440)
    - Philosophical Theology Seminar, nd (Box 25, Folder 441)
    - Polity, nd (Box 25, Folder 442)
    - Readings on Soren Kierkegaard, nd (Box 25, Folder 443)
    - Theological Anthropology, nd (Box 25, Folder 444)
    - Theology of Rudolf Bultmann, nd (Box 25, Folder 445)
    - Tillich Seminar, nd (Box 25, Folder 446)
    - Twentieth Century Literature and Religion (Box 25, Folder 447)
    - Miscellaneous, nd (Box 25, Folder 448)
  - Addendum
    - Yale University and Yale Divinity School
      - REL 214a: Contemporary Roman Catholic Theology, 1988 (Box 72, Folder 158)
      - REL 240a: Comparative Dogmatics, 1969-1973 (Box 72, Folder 159)
      - REL 705b: History of Christian Theology, 1982-1984 (Box 72, Folder 160)
      - REL 705b: History of Christian Theology, 1992 (Box 73, Folder 161)
      - REL 721b: History of Christian Theology in the West, n. d. (Box 73, Folder 162-164)
      - REL 728a: Comparative Doctrine: Ecclesiology, 1989, 1992 (Box 74, Folder 166-168)
      - REL 728a: Comparative Doctrine: notes, 1970-1991 (Box 90, Folder 25)
      - REL 749b: von Balthasar, 1992 (Box 74, Folder 169)
      - REL 891a: Theologies of Religion, 1990 (Box 74, Folder 170)
      - Comparative Doctrine - miscellaneous, 1972-1984 (Box 92, Folder 16)
    - Princeton University
      - REL 361: The Church as Israel, 1993-1994 (Box 74, Folder 171-174)
    - Miscellaneous materials
      - Readings in the History of Exegesis, 1984 (Box 75, Folder 175)
      - Course pack, 1991-1992 (Box 75, Folder 176-177)
      - Student papers, n. d. (Box 75, Folder 178)
      - Comprehensive exam, 1991 (Box 75, Folder 179)
      - Record of dissertations at Yale, n. d. (Box 75, Folder 180)
      - Course syllabi, notes - miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 91, Folder 4)
      - Course syllabi, notes - historical theology, 1984, n.d. (Box 91, Folder 6)
      - Course syllabi, notes - Tillich, 1964, n.d. (Box 91, Folder 7)
- Conferences/Lectures, 1942-2006, n.d.; Series VI
  - Original files
    - "The Day of Redemption or Living with Ourselves", 1942 (Box 26, Folder 449)
    - "The Night was Dark When Jesus Came", 1942 (Box 26, Folder 450)
    - "Consciousness of Sin and Christian Service", 1943 (Box 26, Folder 451)
    - "The Necessity for Persecution", 1943 (Box 26, Folder 452)
    - "1st After Trinity", 1943 (Box 26, Folder 453)
    - "9th After Trinity", 1943 (Box 26, Folder 454)
    - "6th After Epiphany", 1943 (Box 26, Folder 455)
    - "Trinity, 6th Sunday", 1943 (Box 26, Folder 456)
    - "Sunday After New Year", 1943 (Box 26, Folder 457)
    - "Funeral ", 1943 (Box 26, Folder 458)
    - "Whit Sunday", 1943 (Box 26, Folder 459)
    - "Impersonating God", 1944 (Box 26, Folder 460)
    - "Missions, Why?", 1944 (Box 26, Folder 461)
    - "1st in Advent", 1944 (Box 26, Folder 462)
    - "4th After Easter", 1944 (Box 26, Folder 463)
    - "5th After Trinity", 1944 (Box 26, Folder 464)
    - "9th After Trinity", 1944 (Box 26, Folder 465)
    - "10th After Trinity", 1944 (Box 26, Folder 466)
    - "12th After Trinity", 1944 (Box 26, Folder 467)
    - "14th After Trinity", 1944 (Box 26, Folder 468)
    - "China", 1945 (Box 26, Folder 469)
    - "Lutheran League Mission Talk", Georgetown, 1945 (Box 26, Folder 470)
    - "Mother's Day", 1947 (Box 26, Folder 471)
    - "6th Trinity", 1947 (Box 26, Folder 472)
    - "What Then are We to Think?", Canada, 1948-49 (Box 26, Folder 473)
    - To Lutheran Ministers, 1956 (Box 26, Folder 475)
    - "New Roman Catholic Theology and Its Challenge", Ansonia Ministers Club, 1957 (Box 26, Folder 476)
    - "Mariology and the Cult of the Saints", 1959 (Box 26, Folder 477)
    - "Roman Catholic Theologians I", Providence, RI, 1959 (Box 26, Folder 478)
    - "Roman Catholic Theologians II", Providence, RI, 1959 (Box 26, Folder 479)
    - "Roman Catholic I", 1960 (Box 26, Folder 480)
    - "Roman Catholic II", 1960 (Box 26, Folder 481)
    - Augustine Lectures, 1961 (Box 26, Folder 482)
    - Roman Catholic Seminar, 1961 (Box 26, Folder 483)
    - Theological Discussion Group, 1961 (Box 26, Folder 484)
    - Union College, 1962 (Box 26, Folder 485)
    - "Fourth World Conference on Faith and Order"-Montreal, 1963 (Box 26, Folder 486)
    - "Vatican Council", Fairfield University, 1964 (Box 26, Folder 487)
    - Lutheran Faculty Sterrs Conference, 1965 (Box 26, Folder 488)
    - "Roman Catholic Theology", Convocation, 1965 (Box 26, Folder 489)
    - "Significance of the Council to Non-Catholics", Wells College, 1965 (Box 26, Folder 490)
    - "V: Understanding and Working with Roman Catholics", Pittsburgh, 1965 (Box 26, Folder 491)
    - Everybody Goes to the Christian Culture Forum, 1966 (Box 26, Folder 492)
    - "Roman Catholic Theology in Transition", Northwestern Lutheran Seminary, Lecture I, 1966 (Box 26, Folder 493)
    - "Roman Catholic Theology in Transition", Northwestern Lutheran Seminary, Lecture II, 1966 (Box 26, Folder 494)
    - "Roman Catholic Theology in Transition", Northwestern Lutheran Seminary, Lecture III, 1966 (Box 26, Folder 495)
    - Saint Xavier College, 1966 (Box 26, Folder 496)
    - "The Framework of Catholic-Protestant Disagreement" for Saint Xavier conference, 1966 (Box 56, Folder 1303)
    - YDS Chapel, 1966 (Box 26, Folder 497)
    - "Address to Conference of Synodical Presidents/Lutheran Churches in America", Atlanta, 1967 (Box 26, Folder 498)
    - DePauw Chapel Address, 1967 (Box 26, Folder 499)
    - Hamilton, Ontario, 1967 (Box 26, Folder 500)
    - "A Protestant Re-Assessment of the Reformation", St. Mary's Notre Dame, 1967 (Box 26, Folder 501)
    - Southern Conneticut, 1967 (Box 26, Folder 502)
    - "Ecumenicism and the Future of Belief", Gettysburg, 1968 (Box 26, Folder 503)
    - Glen Ellen, 1968 (Box 27, Folder 504)
    - "Interseminary Ecumenical Study Day on the Eucharist", Baltimore, 1968 (Box 27, Folder 505)
    - "Reports on Roman Catholic-Protestant Inter-Confessional Theological Discussion", Singapore, 1968 (Box 27, Folder 506)
    - "Reu Lecture", 1968 (Box 27, Folder 507)
    - "Reu Lecture", 1968 (Box 27, Folder 508)
    - "Ecumenism and the Board of World Mission of the Lutheran Church in America: Foundations, Principles, and Policies", 1969 (Box 27, Folder 509)
    - "The Future of the Dialogue: Pluralism or an Eventual Synthesis of Doctrine?", Villanova University, 1969 (Box 27, Folder 510)
    - "The Future of the Dialogue: Unity Without Synthesis", Villanova University, 1969 (Box 27, Folder 511)
    - "Whither Ecumenism? The Future of the Roman Catholic-Protestant Encounter", Marymount/Tarrytown, 1969 (Box 27, Folder 512)
    - Minutes of Israel Study Meeting, JFK Airport, 1970 (Box 27, Folder 513)
    - Minutes of Israel Study Meeting. La Guardia Airport, 1971 (Box 27, Folder 514)
    - Catholic University Lectures, 1972 (Box 27, Folder 515)
    - Meeting on Ministry, 1972 (Box 27, Folder 516)
    - Psychohistory as a Cultural-Religious Art, 1972 (Box 27, Folder 517)
    - Workshop on Key Questions in Current Theology, 1972 (Box 27, Folder 518)
    - Lectures by Lonergan and Mascall, St. Michael's Institute, 1973 (Box 27, Folder 519)
    - Consultation, 1974 (Box 27, Folder 520)
    - Notre Dame, South Bend, IN, 1974 (Box 27, Folder 521)
    - Seven Theological Schools, New York, 1974 (Box 27, Folder 522)
    - "Address on Infallibility: Responding to Father Kaufman", 1975 (Box 27, Folder 523)
    - "Infallibility", 1975 (Box 27, Folder 524)
    - "Theological Revolutions and the Present Crisis", St. Louis, 1975 (Box 27, Folder 525)
    - "International Review of Theology: Luther Then and Now", 1976 (Box 27, Folder 526)
    - "Augsburg Confession", Philadelphia, 1980 (Box 27, Folder 527)
    - "What is Ecumenism?, Anglican-Lutheran Dialogue", Yale Divinity School, 1981 (Box 27, Folder 528)
    - Emory Conference, 1983 (Box 27, Folder 529)
    - World Council of Churches / International Jewish Committee on Interreligious Consultations conference on "Religious Pluralism: Its Meaning and Lmits in the World Today", Harvard, 1984 (Box 56, Folder 1305)
    - "Begin Uniting Now: An International Approach"-lecture one; "The Gospel and Episcopacy"-lecture two, Southeran Lutheran Seminary, 1985 (Box 27, Folder 530)
    - Reformed Colloquim, 1985 (Box 27, Folder 531)
    - "Thesis V: Episcopal Office", Chicago, 1985 (Box 27, Folder 532)
    - "Theology Since Vatican II", 1985 (Box 27, Folder 533)
    - Karl Barth Symposium, Princeton, NJ, 1986 (Box 27, Folder 534)
    - "The Future of Theological Education in the Lutheran Church: 8th Annual Lutherans in Diaspora Conference", New Haven, 1986 (Box 27, Folder 535)
    - "Non-Theological Factors and Structures of Unity", Chicago, 1986 (Box 27, Folder 536)
    - "Religion and Modern American Intellectual History", Wilson Center Conference, 1986 (Box 27, Folder 537)
    - "Catholic-Lutheran Festival Oct. 25" in The Progress, 1987 (Box 28, Folder 538)
    - "Daedalus and Georgetown University: Religion and Education Planning Conference", 1987 (Box 28, Folder 539)
    - "Does the Bible Have a Postmodern Message?", Boston College, 1987 (Box 28, Folder 540)
    - Eighteenth National Conference of Trinity Institute, New York City, 1987 (Box 28, Folder 541)
    - "Perspectives on the Sacred in Contemporary Theology", 1987 (Box 28, Folder 542)
    - "Theological Perspective: The Waxing and Waning of Religious Belief", 1987 (Box 28, Folder 543)
    - "The Catholic Moment" in National Catholic Register, 1988 (Box 28, Folder 544)
    - "Hans W. Frei and the Future of Theology in America", 1988 (Box 28, Folder 545)
    - H R Niebuhr Conference, Harvard, 1988 (Box 28, Folder 546)
    - The Ratzinger Conference, 1988 (Box 28, Folder 547)
    - "Scripture, Consensus, and Community: Four Lectures on the Church", Austin Presbyterian Seminary, 1988 (Box 28, Folder 549)
    - "Scripture, Consensus and Community", Austin Presbyterian Seminary, 1988 (Box 28, Folder 548)
    - "Luther and Tillich: A Comparison", 1989 (Box 28, Folder 550)
    - "Convocation of Teaching Theologians: Gospel, Church and Ministry", 1990 (Box 28, Folder 551)
    - "Convocation of Teaching Theologians: ELCA Teaching Theologicans at Non-ELCA Schools", 1990 (Box 28, Folder 552)
    - Dulles Colloqium, Union League Club, New York City, 1990 (Box 28, Folder 553)
    - "The Lutheran Movement: Reflections on the Contemporary Situation", Gettysburg, 1990 (Box 28, Folder 554)
    - Lutheran-Roman Catholic Dialogue Committee of New England, Holyoke, MA, 1990 (Box 28, Folder 555)
    - New England Lutheran Clergy Association, Middletown, CT, 1990 (Box 28, Folder 556)
    - Ramsey Colloquium, Union League Club, New York City, 1990 (Box 28, Folder 557)
    - Religion and the Open University, Union League Club, New York City, 1990 (Box 28, Folder 558)
    - St. Joseph's Seminary Seminar, 1990 (Box 28, Folder 559)
    - St. Olaf College, Northfield, MN, 1990 (Box 28, Folder 560)
    - "Confessional Faithfulness and the Ecumenical Failure", Trinity Seminary, Columbus, OH, 1990 (Box 28, Folder 561)
    - "Communio International Catholic Review: The Theology of John Paul II", 1991 (Box 28, Folder 562)
    - "Convocation of Teaching Theologians", Chicago, IL, 1991 (Box 28, Folder 563)
    - "To Be Christian in America Today", Washington Plaza Hotel, 1991 (Box 28, Folder 564)
    - "Tradition and Creativity in Contemporary Culture", Union League Club, New York City, 1992 (Box 28, Folder 565)
    - Fall Faculty Conference, Avon Old Farms Hotel, 1992 (Box 28, Folder 566)
    - "Lutheran Ecumenism: With Whom and How Much?", Pacific Lutheran Theological Seminary, Berkeley, CA, 1992 (Box 28, Folder 567)